trustedsoftware.com 2011-01-14

# Trusted Software Privacy Policy

Last Updated: November 11, 2010. Version 1.0

Trusted Software ApS is committed to protecting your privacy online. This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") discloses how we collect and use information, and the choices that you can make about the way we collect and use your information.

If you are under 18, you should ask your parents or a guardian before you use our Services. If you are not yet 18, do not use our Services; do not download our products.

This Privacy Policy applies to any customers who use our Services. Collection, use, disclosure, and protection of personal information may be subject to different regulations outside the United States. Regardless, if you use our Sites, Products or Services you agree to abide by this policy.

Sites covered by this policy: www.trustedsoftware.com and other sites we own that post a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively "Sites"). This Privacy Policy also applies to software installers created by us (collectively "Software"). This Privacy Policy may also apply to new Sites and Software we develop or decide to distribute. 

## Overview of Our Policy

We supply free and commercial software for Windows on our Sites. Through our partnership with W3i, LLC, the Products on our Sites offer installation of third party software and browser toolbars as part of the installation process. These offers are optional. We refer to our software and Products throughout this agreement as our "Services".

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully so that you understand our online privacy practices regarding information we collect, how we use your information, how we use and share your information and your choices.

We may change this privacy policy. If we change this policy we will post the changes to this privacy statement, our Sites’ homepages, and other places we deem appropriate. We reserve the right to modify this policy at any time. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, or by means of a notice on our home page. 

## Some Terms We Use in This Policy

_Offers_ include advertisements, toolbars and third-party software presented to you during the installation process of software downloaded from our Sites.

_Personally Identifiable Information (PII)_ is any information that identifies or could be used to identify, contact or locate you.

_Partner_ is an advertiser, or other entity with whom we have a business relationship to provide Offers.

_Service_ is the Software downloadable from our Sites, as well as offers presented during installation of those.

_User_ means an individual that has accessed the Sites on which we host our Products or Services.

_We and Our_ refer to Trusted Software ApS.

_You and Your_ refer to each user and his or her agents. 

## Personal Information We Collect

We may collect personal information at various times when you use our Services. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Your participation is voluntary and you have the choice not to disclose any information that we request.

Installation. During installation, we will present you with Offers. You may choose not to accept our Offers. Your participation is voluntary, you are not required to disclose to our Partners any information they request. However, if you provide your Personally Identifiable Information in response to any Offer, we will share it with our Partners so they can provide you with the Offers in which you have expressed interest.

Contacts/IP Information. If you voluntarily submit information or contact us (e.g. password request, technical support), we may keep a record of this communication. We do not merge this information with your Personally Identifiable Information.

Contact Us. We collect your name and email address on the Sites’ “Contact us” forms. We use this information for the sole purpose of responding to your inquiry.

Customer Support. If you use the customer support section on the Sites we will collect your email address, topic and any addition information you provide us. We use this information for the sole purpose of responding to your inquiry. 

## Aggregate Information We Collect

When you use our Services, we may collect tracking information such as your IP address, browser type, the type of operating system you use, details about your computer hardware, the applications you have installed on your PC, the domain name of your Internet service provider, and pages you visited on our Sites. None of the information identifies you personally and we do not link aggregate information to Personally Identifiable Information.

Cookies. A cookie is a small text file sent to your browser. Cookies are stored on your computer's hard drive for record keeping purposes. We and our Partners use session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once you close your browser, the cookie will terminate. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s help file.

We use cookies to: 1) Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing our Services is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage; 2) Allow our Partners to track visits to their sites and stores. This information collected by cookies is sometimes called "clickstream" or "click trail" and may also describe which pages you have seen; 3) Measure certain traffic patterns, for example which of our Sites you have visited. We use this information to understand our users' habits so that we can make each new experience on a Site a better one. We may also use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you will see. We do not store Personally Identifiable Information in our cookies and we do not tie the information in our cookies to our customers’ Personally Identifiable Information

Some of the Partner Offers on our Services may also use cookies. We have no control over our partners’ privacy policies. We also have no control over their cookies, the information collected and its use.

Web beacons or Pixels. We and our Partners may employ a software technology that helps us better manage content on our site. Web beacons or Pixels are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. They track your online Web movement. We embed Pixels invisibly on Web pages. They are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by Pixels to our customers’ Personally Identifiable Information.

Some of the Partner Offers may also use Pixels. We have no control over our partners’ Pixels. We also have no control over how they use information collected.

The Partner Offers displayed during installation of Products from our Sites may record other information. We have no control over that, but you can read the Partner's Privacy Policy directly from the Offer page in the installer. 

## How We Use Your Information

Our primary goal is to make our Services more useful to you. By knowing about you, we and our Partners are able to deliver relevant Services and Offers.

Research. We study users' demographics and interests using your information. We also use cookies, may use pixels, and server log files to better understand and serve you. We compile and analyze this information on an aggregated basis. We also may share this aggregated data periodically with current and potential Partners.

Third Parties and Advertising. Third parties advertise on our Sites and during Product installation. These third parties may seek to use cookies and pixel tags, including those collected on our Site, to track Session Data about the ads you have seen and types of things in which you appear interested. These third parties may also use combined information about your visits to our Site and other sites in order to provide advertisements about related goods and services that may be of interest to you. You can opt-out of the third party advertising program by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp). Opting out of a network does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that the network from which you opted out will no longer deliver ads tailored to your Web preferences and usage patterns.

When you click on a third party advertisers' link from our Site, you will enter the third party's site. We are not responsible for such third party's sites. You should carefully review the privacy statements of any other site you visit, because those privacy statements will apply to your visit to that site, and may be very different from our policy.

## How We Share Your Information

Partners sponsor Offers through the software. You should always assume data collected when you fill-in an Offer will be shared with a Partner. If an Offer requires you to leave our Sites, you should know that our Partners may collect Personally Identifiable Information about you. We do not control these Partner sites. This Privacy Policy does not cover our partners’ websites and information practices. Once you have voluntarily submitted information to our Partners, your personal information is subject to their privacy policy. We have no liability or responsibility for these privacy policies or the use of any Personally Identifiable Information transferred to Partners.

The following describes some of the ways that we may disclose your information to our Partners:

Search Partners. We may transmit your search queries (made on the Sites or within one of our Software Offers) to search Partners, who use this information to provide us with search results, which we then will display to you.

Third-Party Advertisements and Software. When you request or submit your information online to a Partner in response to any Offer, we transfer your information for each request made to that Partner. Once we transfer your Personally Identifiable Information, such information becomes subject to the Partners’ privacy policy.

Legal Disclosure. We may also disclose user information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our policies or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights, property, users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. We may disclose user information, as required by law, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or to comply with a judicial procedure served on our sites; or if the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain service and improve our Products and Services.

Sale, Merger or Asset Transfer. We may buy other businesses or their assets or sell our business assets. Customer information is generally one of the business assets involved in such transactions. Thus, in the event that we or all of our assets are acquired, customer information, including any information collected through the Sites or the Services would be one of the transferred assets.

## Your Choices

Cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you can choose to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or you can reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies, you may be unable to use our Services.  

## Security

We do not knowingly collect information about children under the age of 13. We encourage parents and guardians to be familiar with the web sites that their children visit. The Federal Trade Commission ("FTC") regulates the means by which web site operators collect and use personal information from children under 13, pursuant to the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (the "Act"). For more information about the Act and children's on-line privacy in general, visit the FTC's web site at [www.ftc.gov/privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy). For safety tips on privacy visit [www.OnGuardOnline.gov](http://www.onguardonline.gov/). 

## Miscellaneous Provisions

YOUR USE OF OUR SERVICES IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. OUR SERVICES (INCLUDING ALL CONTENT AND FUNCTIONS MADE AVAILABLE ON OR ACCESSED THROUGH OUR SITES) IS PROVIDED "AS IS." WE MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND WHATSOEVER ABOUT: (1) THE ACCURACY, MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT; (2) THE SERVER THAT MAKES THE SERVICES AVAILABLE, INCLUDING THAT IT IS FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER COMPONENTS THAT MAY INFECT, HARM, OR CAUSE DAMAGE TO YOUR COMPUTER EQUIPMENT OR ANY OTHER PROPERTY WHEN YOU ACCESS, BROWSE, DOWNLOAD FROM, OR OTHERWISE USE THE SITE.

UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO OUR NEGLIGENCE, SHALL WE BE LIABLE FOR ANY CONSEQUENTIAL, DIRECT, INCIDENTAL, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, OR SPECIAL DAMAGES RELATED TO (A) THE USE OF, (B) THE INABILITY TO USE, OR (C) ERRORS OR OMISSIONS IN THE CONTENTS AND FUNCTIONS OF OUR SITES AND SERVICES, EVEN IF WE OR OUR REPRESENTATIVES HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. SOME STATES DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, SO THE ABOVE LIMITATION OR EXCLUSION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU. IN NO EVENT SHALL OUR TOTAL LIABILITY TO YOU FOR ALL DAMAGES, LOSSES, AND CAUSES OF ACTION (WHETHER IN CONTRACT OR TORT, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) EXCEED $10.00.

Indemnification. You agree to indemnify, defend, and hold us and all of our agents, directors, employees, information providers, licensors and licensees, officers, and subsidiaries (collectively, "Indemnified Parties") harmless from and against any and all liability and costs (including, without limitation, attorneys' fees and costs) incurred by you in connection with any claim arising out of any breach by you of this Privacy Policy. You will cooperate as fully as reasonably required in our defense of any claim. We reserve the right, at our own expense, to assume the exclusive defense and control of any matter otherwise subject to indemnification by you and you shall not in any event settle any matter without our written consent.

International Policy. Our Services are hosted by servers in the United States. Accordingly, if you are located outside of the United States, we will transfer the personal information you provide to us to the United States. By submitting your personal information, you fully understand and consent, to its transfer, storage and processing in the United States.

Enforcement / Redress. If you feel that we have not followed our Privacy policy, please let us know. Also, if you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy policy, its implementation, or would like a written copy, please feel free to contact us at: Trusted Software ApS, Blomsterhaven 42, DK-4300 Holbaek, Denmark.
